<resources>

    <string name="choose_language">Select a language</string>
    <string-array name="languages">
        <item>Russian</item>
        <item>English</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="locale">Язык</string>
    <string name="language_russian">Русский</string>
    <string name="language_english">Английский</string>

    <string name="choose_theme">Select the application theme</string>
    <string-array name="theme">
        <item>Light theme</item>
        <item>Dark theme</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="light_theme">Light theme</string>
    <string name="dark_theme">Dark theme</string>

    <string name="pref_key_theme">theme_preference</string>


    <string name="rules_chess">
        Chess is a strategic board game for two players who move their pieces on a game
        board with the goal of capturing the opponent king.\n\n
        The game is played on a square board consisting of 64 squares arranged in 8 rows with 8 squares in each row.\n\n
        Each player controls an army of 16 pieces: a king, a queen, two rooks, two knights, two bishops, and eight pawns.\n\n
        The objective of the game is to threaten the opponent king with a "check" in such a way that the opponent cannot prevent its capture.\n\n
        The pieces have different abilities to move:\n\n
        The king can move to an adjacent square in any direction.\n
        The queen can move any number of squares vertically, horizontally, or diagonally.\n
        The rook can move any number of squares vertically or horizontally.\n
        The bishop can move any number of squares diagonally.\n
        The knight can move to a square that is two squares horizontally or vertically and then one square perpendicular to that.\n
        The pawn can move forward one square or, on its first move, two squares. It can capture opponent pieces by moving diagonally one square.\n
        Players take turns, starting with the player controlling the white pieces.\n\n
        A move consists of moving one piece to a vacant square according to its movement rules.\n\n
        If a piece lands on a square occupied by an opponent piece, it captures the opponent piece, and the opponent removes it from the board.\n\n
        If the king is threatened with a check, the player must prevent its capture by moving the king or defending it with another piece.\n\n
        If the king cannot be saved from capture, it is declared "checkmate," and the game ends in favor of the opponent.
    </string>

    <string name="rules_checkers">
        The game board of checkers consists of a 64-square grid, arranged in 8 rows of 8 squares each.
        The initial setup of the game is as follows: black checkers occupy the bottom three rows,
        and white checkers occupy the top three rows.\n\n
        The objective of the game is to capture or block all of the opponent checkers.\n\n
        Checkers can only move diagonally to an empty square in a forward direction (opposite to the
        color of the checkers).\n\n
        A regular checker can move one square forward diagonally. It cannot move backward unless it
        becomes a king.\n\n
        When a checker reaches the last row of the opponent side, it becomes a king. A king can
        move both forward and backward diagonally.\n\n
        A checker can capture an opponent checker if there is an empty square behind it and there
        is an empty square on the opposite diagonal after the opponent checker. In this case, the
        checker jumps over the opponent checker and occupies the empty square behind it. If there
        is another capture opportunity after capturing one checker, the player can continue capturing
        in the same turn.\n\n
        If a checker reaches the edge of the board and there are no obstacles on the opposite diagonal,
        it becomes a king.\n\n
        Players take turns moving their checkers. A move consists of moving one of their checkers to
        an adjacent empty square.\n\n
        If a player cannot make a move, their turn is skipped. If a player cannot make a move multiple
        times in a row, they lose the game.\n\n
        The game ends when one of the players captures or blocks all of the opponent checkers.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="app_name">Сheckers &amp; Сhess</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="CheckersChess">Checkers &amp; Chess</string>
    <string name="playsCheckers">Play Checkers</string>
    <string name="playsChess">Play Chess</string>
    <string name="exitMain">Exit</string>
    <string name="statistics">Statistics</string>

    <string name="languageSettings">Language</string>
    <string name="designSettings">Design</string>
    <string name="themeSettings">Theme</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>

    <string name="lvl1">Easy level:</string>
    <string name="lvl2">Average level:</string>
    <string name="lvl3">Difficult level:</string>

    <string name="chess">Сhess</string>
    <string name="play">Play</string>
    <string name="rules">Rules</string>
    <string name="difficultyLevel">Difficulty level</string>

    <string name="checkers">Checkers</string>

    <string name="time">Time</string>

    <string name="switch_theme_summary">Enable dark theme</string>


</resources>